<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on A minimal Hugo website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on A minimal Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blog posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/</guid>
      <description>Posts Interim analysis for early stopping during the study Predicting the probability of rejecting H0 before running the study Bayesian analysis of a very simple example</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interim analysis for early stopping during the study</title>
      <link>/post/2021/07/29/interim-analysis-for-early-stopping-during-the-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021/07/29/interim-analysis-for-early-stopping-during-the-study/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the second of three posts that address:
1. Predicting the probability of a “positive” (reject \(H_{0}\)) study before running the study
2. Interim analyses during the study
3. Evaluating study data in a meaningful way after the study is completed.
The first post is available here.
Interim analyses of an ongoing clinical trial enable early stopping due to efficacy or futility. Clinical trials that involve interims data looks are often referred to as group sequential trials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting the probability of rejecting H0 before running the study</title>
      <link>/post/2021/07/27/predicting-the-probability-of-rejecting-h0-before-running-the-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021/07/27/predicting-the-probability-of-rejecting-h0-before-running-the-study/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the first of three posts that address:
1. Predicting the probability of a “positive” (reject \(H_{0}\)) study before running the study
2. Interim analyses during the study
3. Evaluating study data in a meaningful way after the study is completed.
Topic 2. and 3. will be posted later.
The general linear modelConsider the general linear model with a single factor (One-way ANOVA) for a mean centered variable \(Y_{ij}\), \(Y_{ij}=Z_{ij}-\overline{Z}\):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian analysis of a very simple example</title>
      <link>/post/2021/07/25/bayesian-analysis-of-a-very-simple-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021/07/25/bayesian-analysis-of-a-very-simple-example/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionIn this post I´ll explore some basic approaches to analyze a simple simulated data example.
Two sample continuous outcomeConsider a dependent variable Y and an independent variable X (two levels, A and B).Standardize Y to get zero mean and unit standard deviation.
DAT &amp;lt;- tibble(N = 60 , X = rbinom(N, 1, 0.5),Y = 0.5*X + rnorm(N)) %&amp;gt;% mutate(X = factor(X, labels = c(&amp;quot;A&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;B&amp;quot;)) , Y = (Y-mean(Y, na.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo XMin</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>XMin is the . The original reason that I wrote it was I needed a minimal example of Hugo themes when I was writing the blogdown book. Basically I wanted a simple theme that supports a navigation menu, a home page, other single pages, lists of pages, blog posts, categories, tags, and RSS. That is all. Nothing fancy. In terms of CSS and JavaScript, I really want to keep them minimal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief CV</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>full CV available upon request
PERSONAL DATA Name: David Bock Year of birth: 1976 Office address:
 Biostatistics, School of Public Health and Community Medicine, Institute of Medicine, Göteborg University, Göteborg University, Sweden SSORG, Sahlgrenska University Hospital/Östra, Sweden  Email: david.bock@gu.se (work) Email: davidbock76@gmail.com (personal/consulting)
CURRENT POSITIONS  11/2019 - : Senior lecturer, School of Public Health and Community Medicine, Institute of Medicine, Göteborg University 8/2014 - : Researcher, Scandinavian Surgical Outcome Research Group (SSORG), Institute of Clinical Sciences, Göteborg University 8/2019 - : Biostatistical consultant (freelance part time)  PREVIOUS POSITIONS  8/2014 –11/2019: Researcher, Department of Public Health and Community Medicine, Sahlgrenska Academy, Göteborg University 3/2006 – 8/2014: Statistician, AstraZeneca R&amp;amp;D Mölndal, Sweden  ACADEMIC DEGREES  2/2019: Associate professor (epidemiology), Sahlgrenska Academy, Göteborg University 1/2005: Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical consultancy</title>
      <link>/statistical_consultancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/statistical_consultancy/</guid>
      <description>I have a broad experience ranging from pharmaceutical drug development to design and analysis of epidemiological studies and prediction models.
I undertake statistical consulting assignments. For example:
 Courses/workshops/teaching Study design &amp;ndash;	Sample size calculation &amp;ndash;	Study protocol input &amp;ndash;	Probability of success Statistical Analysis Plan Research manuscript input Data monitoring committee Prediction models Bayesian analysis Go/No Go criteria  If interested, please contact me at: davidbock76@gmail.com
Testimonials are available.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
